interface Question {
  question: string;
  option1: string;
  option2: string;
  option3: string;
  option4: string;
  ans: number
}

export const data:Question[] = [
    {
      question: "What material can be recycled infinitely without losing quality?",
      option1: "Paper",
      option2: "Glass",
      option3: "Plastic",
      option4: "Aluminum",
      ans: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "What is the main goal of the circular economy?",
      option1: "To produce more waste",
      option2: "To minimize resource consumption",
      option3: "To maximize production of goods",
      option4: "To increase environmental pollution",
      ans: 2,
    },
    {
      question: "What is the key concept of the circular economy?",
      option1: "Recycling only glass",
      option2: "Reduce, Reuse, Recycle",
      option3: "Increase plastic production",
      option4: "Throw everything in the trash",
      ans: 2,
    },
    {
      question: "What are the three pillars of the circular economy?",
      option1: "Reduction, Reuse, Recovery",
      option2: "Recycling, Reusing, Saving",
      option3: " Breakage, Repair, Recycling",
      option4: " Reduction, Research, Recycling",
      ans: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following items can be considered an example of recycling?",
      option1: "Plastic bottle transformed into clothing fabric",
      option2: "Burnt paper",
      option3: " Glass thrown in the trash",
      option4: "Plastic disposed of in the ocean",
      ans: 1,
    },
    {
      question: 'What does "upcycling" mean in the context of the circular economy?',
      option1: "Transforming waste into new products of higher value",
      option2: " Disposing waste in landfills",
      option3: "Reusing the same materials",
      option4: " Not recycling at all",
      ans: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following actions helps promote the circular economy?",
      option1: "Using disposable products",
      option2: "Throwing everything in the trash bin",
      option3: "Buying products packaged in plastic",
      option4: "Purchasing durable and recyclable products",
      ans: 4,
    },
    {
      question: "What is one of the main advantages of the circular economy over the linear model?",
      option1: "Increased resource consumption",
      option2: "Reduced production costs",
      option3: "Greater environmental pollution",
      option4: "Limited community involvement",
      ans: 2,
    },
    {
      question: "What is one of the main obstacles to the adoption of the circular economy?",
      option1: " Low awareness of the importance of recycling",
      option2: "Ease of waste disposal",
      option3: "High availability of natural resources",
      option4: "Limited interest from companies",
      ans: 1,
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following concepts is NOT related to the circular economy?",
      option1: "Recycling",
      option2: "Zero waste",
      option3: "Excessive consumption",
      option4: "Reuse",
      ans: 3,
    },
  ];